Finding Aid for Neuroscience Program (University of Michigan) records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Neuroscience Program (University of Michigan) records 1963-1985
University of Michigan. Neuroscience Program.
1 linear foot
861043 Bimu C7 2
Neuroscience Program course materials, correspondence, evaluations, and related material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Records received from Neuroscience Department, Stephen S. Easter, chairman, November 27, 1985. (Donor No. 7264 )
The collection is open for general research.
The Neuroscience Committee was organized in January, 1966 to establish and interdisciplinary, graduate-level introductory course in the neuro-biological area. The course (Neuroscience 690 and 691, jointly listed in the Departments of Anatomy, Physiology, Zoology, Psychology, and Pharmacology) provided a multi-disciplinary background to first-level graduate students interested in the nervous system. In 1970, the Neuroscience Committee established an Interdepartmental degree program in the Neurosciences. This doctoral program, by 1982, offered course through the participating departments of: Anatomy, Biological Chemistry, Biostatistics, Biological Sciences, Computer and Communications Sciences, Electrical and Computer Engineering, Neurology, Ophthalmology, Pathology, Pharmacology, Physiology, Psychiatry, and Psychology.
The Neuroscience Program collection consists of one linear foot of material, arranged by topic. The 31 folders in the collection are open for general research.
The first two folders, Neuroscience Degree Program Planning, 1963-1982, contain information about the curriculum and its inception. Early correspondence regarding the need for a Neuroscience Program at the University of Michigan is included.
Ten of the 31 folders in the collection contain Neuroscience 690-691 materials. These are arranged by year, 1966-1976, and contain lecture schedules, seminar information, copies of the midterm and final examinations, and class evaluations. Materials pertaining to Neuroscience 731, Neurology 621 622, and Biological Science classes are arranged in individual folders as well. Information regarding other classes in the Neuroscience Program is arranged under Miscellaneous Course Announcement, and interdepartmental Memos and Miscellaneous Correspondence. The Preliminary Examination folders contain, in addition to copies of the exams themselves, correspondence among faculty members regarding proposals for questions and exam times.
The final two folders contain the Summary Reports of Rackham Administrative Council Meetings from 1975 1964.
Subjects:
Neurology.; University of Michigan. Neuroscience Program.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Neuroscience Program.
- Administrative Records
  - Neuroscience Degree Program Planning, 1963 1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Interdepartmental Correspondence Regarding Neuroscience Committee Membership, 1969 198o (Box 1)
  - Neuroscience Committee Minutes, 1968 1980 (Box 1)
  - Neuroscience Committee Reports regarding Status of Previous Students, 1976 1981 (Box 1)
  - Neuroscience 690 691 Miscellaneous Papers, 1966 1976 (l0 folders) (Box 1)
  - Neuroscience 731 Miscellaneous Papers, 1978 1983 (Box 1)
  - Neurology 621 622 Miscellaneous Papers, 1973 1977 (Box 1)
  - Biological Sciences Miscellaneous Papers, 1980 1983 (Box 1)
  - Neuroscience Preliminary Examinations, 1974 1979, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Course Announcements, 1965 1981 (Box 1)
  - Interdepartmental Memos and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969¬1983, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Summary Reports of Rackham. Administrative Council Meetings, 1975 1984, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Training Funding, 1973-1985 (Box 1)